A racing second hand, a shooting comet,
،عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
a pop-up doll, and broken ceramic!
دمية آلية الخروج وخزف محطّم
Mystery-solving logic is helpful against people's dry hearts!
المنطق المفكّك للغموض مفيد في مواجهة القلوب الجافّة
Today's a beautiful illustrator! Her mischievous streak means death!
،قضيّة اليوم عن رسّامة توضيحية حسناء !حبّ العبث يقود للموت
He sees the single truth for what it is, and there's no outwitting him!
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة، وباستنتاجات لا مُضاهٍ لها
His name? Detective Conan!
!إنّه المتحرّي كونان
The Illustrator Murder Case.
جريمة قتل الرسّامة التوضيحية
Hanaoka Design Office
مكتب هاناوكا للتصميم
Eh? A collection of
ماذا؟ مجموعة رسومات مسارح جريمة؟
I didn't tell you? It's being released next month
لم أخبرك؟ ستصدر الشهر القادم
by painter and president of this design office, Hanaoka-sensei!
من رسّام ورئيس مكتب التصميم هذا، هاناوكا سينسي
I asked both of you to come today for an interview
طلبت منكما الاثنان القدوم اليوم لإجراء مقابلة
to put at the end of the collection...
نضيفها في ختامية المجموعة
Interview?
مقابلة؟
Is something wrong?
أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
It's just that Dad said it was a collection of paintings of him!
قال أبي أنّها ستكون مجموعة رسمات له
It seemed strange, huh?
بدا ذلك غير منطقيّ، صحيح يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah!
أجل
So, where is this fancy painter?
إذاً، أين الرسّام رفيع المقام هذا؟
He's still not here.
لم يأت بعد
He could be asleep in his studio...
ربما لا يزال نائماً في الاستوديو
Gimme a break.
...بربك
Beika Apartment Building #2
مجمع شقق بيكا 2
What are you doing?
ما-ما الذي تفعلينه؟
Oh, you woke up.
استيقظت
Painter - Kenjin Hanaoka (48)
هاناوكا كينجين (48) - رسّام
What is this? Paint?
ما هذا؟ طلاء؟
Nail polish.
طلاء أظافر
Illustrator - Izumi Chono (25)
تشونو إيزومي (25) - رسّامة توضيحية
Isn't it a nice color? lt went on sale today!
أليس لونه جميلاً؟ بدأ بيعه اليوم
Really, now...
...يا إلهي
Should you really be relaxing?
ألديك وقت للاسترخاء حقاً؟
Aren't you supposed to meet some detective at 5:00?
ألم يكن يُفترض بك لقاء مُتحرٍّ ما عند الخامسة؟
Oh no!
!تبّاً
Hurry.
أسرع
I put your pants and socks on for you.
ألبستُك بنطالك وجواربك
Don't pull that prank anymore! If my wife were to see it-
...لا تقومي بهذا المقلب مُجدداً، لو رأته زوجتي
That's why I did it.
لذا قمتُ به
That way she'd divorce you and we could be together.
عندها ستطلّقك ويمكننا البقاء معاً
What was that for?!
!لـ-لمَ هذا؟
I told you our relationship is business only!
أخبرتك أنّ علاقتنا علاقة عمل فقط
That's why you're able to paint whatever you want
لذا يمكنك رسم أيّ ما تشائين
and live in such a fancy apartment!
والعيش في شقّة فارهة كهذه
I'll reveal the truth!
!سأكشف الحقيقة
She's already vaguely suspicious. But she overlooks it.
إنّها تشك بالفعل، لكنّها تتغاضى عن الأمر
I don't mean us. I mean the paintings.
لم أقصد أمرنا، بل الرسومات
Sixty percent of your paintings were actually done by me.
ستّون بالمئة من رسماتك كانت من تنفيذي أنا
Wait!
مهلك
If word gets out, you can kiss your reputation goodbye.
إذا تسرّبت الحقيقة، ستتبخر سمعتك
You won't be able to sell a single painting.
لن تستطيع بيع رسمة واحدة
Who'd ever believe a new illustrator?!
من سيصدّق رسامة توضيحية مبتدئة؟
Oh, you didn't know? I clearly marked each one I drew.
لم تعرف؟ وضعتُ علامةً على كلّ رسمة لي
What?!
!ما-ماذا؟
The World of Kenjin Hanaoka
عالم هاناوكا كينجين
Take a good look beneath your signature on the paintings I did.
أمعن النظر تحت توقيعك على الرسمات التي كانت من تنفيذي
This is--
...هـ-هذا
I've placed that mark on all of my original works.
وضعتُ تلك العلامة على كلّ أعمالي الأصلية
Thanks to your increase in work, they've become rather famous...
أصبحت علامتي مشهورةً بسبب ازدهار عملك
I stayed up all night painting another.
سهرتُ البارحة في إنهاء رسمة أخرى
Be sure to have it delivered to the publisher later.
احرص على أن توصلها للناشر لاحقاً
Try as you might, there's no escape from me...
...مهما حاولت، فلن تستطيع الفرار مني
...for as long as you live.
طيلة حياتك
He's late! It's already 5:30!
!تأخّر! تجاوزت الخامسة والنصف
No luck. He's not at home, and I get his machine at the studio.
لا جدوى. ليس في منزله، وأتلقى الردّ الآلي عندما أتّصل بالاستوديو
Maybe Chono-kun's place? Today was her deadline...
،ربما يكون في منزل تشونو-كن فاليوم هو موعد التسليم النهائي لها
Chono?
تشونو؟
A new illustrator. She lives in that building right there.
رسّامة توضيحية جديدة، تعيش في ذاك المبنى هناك
Damn it! I didn't mean to kill her!
تبّاً! لم أقصد... لم أقصد قتلها
Hello, this is Chono. I'm away at the moment.
مرحباً، أنا تشونو. لست متوفرة حالياً
Please leave your message after the tone.
اترك رسالتك بعد سماع الصافرة من فضلك
Hello. This is Tanaka from Hanaoka Design.
مرحباً، أنا تاناكا من مكتب تصميم هاناوكا
Chono-kun. Are you there?
أأنتِ موجودة يا تشونو-كن؟
Hanaoka Design!
!مرحباً، مكتب تصميم هاناوكا
Hello? Hello?
مرحباً؟ مرحباً؟
Who is it?
ماذا هناك؟
A prank call.
اتّصال عابث
What are you looking at, Conan-kun?
ما الذي تنظر له يا كونان-كن؟
That apartment's veranda.
شرفة تلك الشقّة
Oh, my...
...عجباً
They left their mattress out in the rain.
تركوا الفرشة خارجاً مع أن المطر يهطل
Ah. That's Chono-kun's apartment.
تلك شقّة تشونو-كن
Guess she's asleep.
ربما هي نائمة
This is taking far too long! Sorry, but I'm leaving.
هذا تأخير فوق المعقول! آسف، لكني سأغادر
Please, wait!
!ا-انتظر
Mori-san!
!موري-سان
Hanaoka-sensei!
!هاناوكا سينسي
Where were you?
أين كنت؟
Sorry about that.
آسف، آسف
I fell asleep in my studio...
غلبني النوم في الاستوديو
Your studio? We called there several times...
الاستوديو؟ اتّصلنا به عدّة مرات
Yes, that's what woke me up...
أجل، أيقظني الرنين وقتها
Sorry to keep you waiting, Detective Mori!
!أعتذر على جعلك تنتظر حضرة المتحرّي موري
Huh? What happened to your fingernail?
ماذا؟ ما خطب أظافرك؟
My fingernail?
أظافري؟
Is that nail polish?
أهذا طلاء أظافر؟
Of course not! It's just paint!
!بالطبع لا! مجرد طلاء رسم
Must've gotten it in my studio.
لا بدّ أنه علق بي في الاستوديو
Oh, Tanaka-kun. Chono-kun might call.
بالمناسبة يا تاناكا-كن، قد تتّصل تشونو-كن
Transfer the call to me if she does.
أعطني السمّاعة عندما تفعل
Right!
حاضر
Damn! Damn! Damn that woman!
!تبّاً... تبّاً! تبّاً
Hanaoka Design!
!مرحباً، مكتب تصميم هاناوكا
Hello, this is Chono.
مرحباً، أنا تشونو
Oh, it's you! Just a second!
!إنّها أنت! انتظري لحظة
Sir! It's Chono-kun!
سينسي، إنّها تشونو-كن
This is Hanaoka. Are you feeling any better?
معك هاناوكا، أتشعرين بتحسن الآن؟
What? You're going to die?!
!ماذا؟ ستموتين؟
You're going to jump off the veranda?!
!ستقفزين من الشرفة؟
She jumped off!
!قـ-قفزت
The deceased is Izumi Chono, 25 years old.
المُتوفاة هي تشونو إيزومي-سان، 25 عاماً
Hanaoka-san. She was an illustrator for your design firm, correct?
هاناوكا-سان، كانت رسّامةً توضيحية في مكتب تصميمك، صحيح؟
Yes. She was still new, but she had a keen sense.
أجل، كانت مبتدئة لكن تمتلك حسّاً دقيقاً
But on the phone she said she was going to die since she had no talent...
لكنّها أخبرتني على الهاتف أنّ لا موهبة لها، وأنّها ستموت
...the next thing I knew, she had jumped off the veranda...
وبعدها فوراً، كانت قد قفزت من الشرفة
And you all witnessed it?
هل شهدتم جميعاً ذلك؟
Yes...
أجل
A contact lens?
عدسات لاصقة؟
Wait. Wasn't she--
...لحظة، ألم تكن
With so many witnesses, it must've been a suicide...
بوجود هذا العدد من الشاهدين، يبدو أنّه كان انتحاراً
No! This was a murder!
!كلا، كانت جريمة قتل
I bet she was dead before she fell,
لا بدّ أنها كانت ميتة قبل سقوطها
and that someone pushed her over!
ورماها أحدهم
In which case, the most suspicious is...
...ما يعني أن الأكثر شبهة
...this man, who tried to talk her out of suicide!
هو هذا الشخص الذي حاول منعها من القفز على الهاتف
Could an accomplice have pushed her?!
أكان له متواطئ دفعها؟
No, there was no one on the veranda when she fell.
كلا، لم يكن هناك أحد على الشرفة عندما سقطت
Then how did he push her off from so far away?!
!كيف رماها إذاً... من تلك المسافة البعيدة؟
Say, isn't this strange?
ألا تجدون هذا غريباً؟
Look at her eyes. She's wearing contacts.
انظروا لعينيها، ترتدي عدسات لاصقة
What about it?
ما في ذلك؟
But she was wearing glasses when she fell.
لكنّها كانت ترتدي نظارات عندما سقطت
Who wears glasses when they already have contacts in?
من قد يرتدي نظّارات وبعينيه عدسات لاصقة سلفاً؟
He has a point...
...معه حق
In other words, someone put her glasses on before pushing her off?
ما يعني أنّ أحداً وضع نظّارتها عليها وأسقطها؟
Hold on!
!انتظروا
Detective. You saw her jump off for yourself.
!حضرة المتحرّي، رأيت تشونو-كن تقفز بأم عينيك
There was nobody else on the veranda at the time.
لم يكن هناك أحد سواها على الشرفة آنذاك
Chono
تشونو
Oh? The door's unlocked...
ماذا؟ الباب غير مقفل
A nail...
...مسمار
What's it doing here?
لمَ هو هنا؟
Alright, you!
!أنت
Ran! Watch this kid!
!ران! راقبي هذا الصبيّ
So this is the veranda she jumped off of...
هذه الشرفة التي سقطت منها إذاً
Slippers, a cell phone, and a broken flowerpot...
خفّان، هاتف خلويّ، وأصيص مكسور
The flowerpot pieces lead to the drain...
تقود آثار الأصيص لفتحة التصريف
You know you shouldn't sneak around alone!
تعرف أنّ عليك عدم العبث في المكان
A contact lens case. I assume it's hers.
حافظة عدسات لاصقة، يبدو أنّها لها
In which case, those glasses are the issue...
ما يعني أنّ تلك النظّارة هي المشكلة
She probably forgot she was wearing contacts.
لا بدّ أنها نسيت ارتداءها لعدسات لاصقة
Let's search the place! If this was a suicide, there might be a will!
لنفتّش المكان جيّداً، قد تكون هناك وصيّة إذا كان هذا انتحاراً
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
What's with these pictures?
ما خطب هذه الصور؟
Those are photos she took on a recent company trip.
إنّها صور التقطتها تشونو-كن في رحلة لعاملي المكتب مؤخراً
She liked drawing on people in their sleep.
كانت تحبّ تنفيذ مقالب على الأشخاص النائمين
It looks like they're all the same pattern.
يبدو أنّها نفس الرسمة على الجميع
That's her signature.
ذاك توقيعها
The butterfly comes from the 'cho' in her name,
الفراشة من لفظ "تشو" في اسمها
and she always puts it on her art.
كانت ترسمها في كلّ أعمالها
Her illustrations have gotten popular lately...
أصبحت شعبية رسوماتها ترتفع مؤخراً
No will in here either...
لا وصيّة في هذه الغرفة أيضاً
Inspector Megure. There was nail polish on the floor.
مفتّش ميغوري، يوجد طلاء أظافر على الأرض
I think that's the nail polish that went on sale today.
أظنّه طلاء الأظافر الذي بدأ بيعه اليوم
Everyone at school talked about its unique color.
كان الجميع في المدرسة يتكلمون عن لونه الفريد
Say, isn't that what's on this sheet?
أليس هو ما على اللحاف أيضاً؟
No question about it!
!لا شكّ
But she didn't have any on her hands or feet.
لكنها لم تضع أيّاً منه على يديها أو قدميها
The only person wearing this color was...
...الوحيد الذي كان به هذا اللون
...you, huh?
هو أنت يا سيّد، أليس كذلك؟
Is this true?
أهذا صحيح؟
It just happened to be paint of the same color!
!صادف أن يكون طلاءً بنفس اللون
I was working in my studio until this morning.
فقد كنتُ أعمل في الاستوديو حتّى الصباح
He's the killer. No question about it.
لا شكّ في الأمر، إنّه القاتل
But he was in the office when she fell.
لكنّه كان في المكتب عندما سقطتْ
And with us!
كما معنا نحن
We're leaving now, Conan-kun!
!سنغادر الآن يا كونان-كن
No! Just a little longer--
...كلا! أريد البقاء أكثر
Disinfecting solution!
!محلول تعقيم
That's odd. Judging from that case, she had soft lenses!
غريب، كانت عدساتها اللاصقة من الصنف الرقيق بناءً على الحافظة
There was only disinfectant in the fridge.
يوجد محلول تعقيم فحسب في الثلّاجة
Where's the saline solution?!
أين المحلول الملحيّ؟
Inspector Megure. We haven't found a will.
مفتّش ميغوري، لم نجد أيّ وصية
Maybe it wasn't a suicide?
...ربما لم يكن انتحاراً
Excuse me...
...المعذرة
I'm a courier.
أنا عامل توصيل
I forgot to leave a pick-up receipt when I came earlier.
نسيتُ ترك إيصال استلام عندما أتيت قبلاً
Earlier?
قبلاً؟
Around 6:30.
عند السادسة والنصف
6:30?! That's when she jumped!
!السادسة والنصف؟ عندما قفزت
Did you see her then?!
هل رأيتها آنذاك إذاً؟
No, I was told I could pick it up just inside the doorway
كلا، تمّ إخباري أن بإمكاني أخذ الرسمات بجوار الباب عندما أفتحه
and to come at exactly 6:30. I didn't actually meet anyone.
وأن آتي عند السادسة والنصف، فلم أقابل أحداً
Here's today's pick-up receipt.
هذا إيصال استلام اليوم
Hanaoka?!
!هاناوكا؟
It says you were the one who requested the pick-up.
مكتوبٌ أنّك من طلب الاستلام يا هاناوكا-سان
What's the deal?
ما الموضوع؟
A courier at exactly the same time she dies-- seems fishy to me.
...عامل توصيل في نفس وقت موتها هناك ما يبدو مريباً لي
She told me over the phone that she finished a painting
أ-أخبرتني على الهاتف أنّها أنهت رسمةً
so I simply arranged for a courier to deliver it to the editors.
فرتّبتُ لأن يأخذها عامل توصيل ويعطيها للناشر فحسب
She was tired and seemed odd,
بدت بحالٍ غريبة وكانت مرهقة
so I made it so she wouldn't have to wait on the courier.
فلم أجعلها تنتظر قدوم عامل التوصيل
Did anything seem odd when you entered the apartment?
أكان هناك أمرٌ غريب عندما دخلت الشقّة؟
Now that you mention it, the door slammed right open.
بذكرك ذلك، انفتح الباب قوّة
I had barely even touched it...
رغم أنّي بالكاد لمسته
You sure she didn't do it?
أمتأكد أنّها لم تكن من فتحه؟
I thought so myself, but there was no one there.
ذلك ما ظننته، لكن لم أجد أحداً
A nail fell, that's all.
سقط مسمار لا أكثر
A nail?
مسمار؟
Yeah. And then I heard something in the back break.
أجل، ثمّ سمعت صوت انكسار في الخلف
Wait a minute!
!لحظة
Perfect! It's stuck on part of the flowerpot!
!مثاليّ! إنّه عالق بجزء من الأصيص
I've figured it all out! With this trick, it'd be possible to push her off
فهمتُ كلّ شيء! سيمكن إسقاطها من الشرفة ...باستعمال هذه الحيلة
the veranda from even miles away!
!ولو ابتعدت عشرات الكيلومترات
I've figured out the killer's trick!
!اكتشفتُ الحيلة التي استعملها القاتل
What're you doing?! I thought you left!
!ما الذي تفعله؟ ظننتك غادرت
Ow! Stupid mosquitoes!
...مؤلم! الناموس الحقير
And now I put this Button Speaker on the old man...
...أضع الآن الزرّ المكبّر للصوت على العمّ
Eh? You know who did it?!
ماذا؟ عرفت هويّة القاتل؟
Yes. Chono-san didn't commit suicide. She was murdered!
أجل، لم تنتحر تشونو-سان، بل قُتلت
By you, Hanaoka-san!
وأنت من قتلها يا هاناوكا-سان
Hold on, Mori-kun. You know he couldn't have done it.
رويدك يا موري-كن، أنت تعي أنّه لم يكن بمقدوره فعلها
Yeah! He couldn't be the killer!
!صحيح، يستحيل أن يكون القاتل
We were all in that office when we saw the lady fall!
فقد كنّا في المكتب جميعاً عندما !رأينا المرأة تسقط
That's right!
!أجل
Quiet! He most certainly could have done it!
!اخرس! كان بإمكانه فعلها
He just needed strong fishing line and a nail!
احتاج لخيط صيد متين ومسمار لا أكثر
Inspector Megure. Can you get some?
مفتّش ميغوري، هلّا وفرتهما؟
Yes...
...حـ-حسناً
And a soy sauce bottle and hot coffee.
كما علبة صلصة صويا وقهوة ساخنة
A soy sauce bottle and coffee?
علبة صلصة صويا وقهوة؟
We're heating the coffee at the moment,
نعدّ القهوة حالياً
but what are you trying to do here?
لكن ما الذي تنوي فعله بالضبط؟
Please just humor me, if you would.
افعل ما سأمليه عليك الآن من فضلك
First, make a loop that's long enough to go
بدايةً، اصنع حلقة طويلةً بخيط الصيد
from the veranda's railing to the door and back.
تمتد من سور الشرفة إلى الباب
Pull one end through the belt on the mattress, which'll be our victim,
مرر طرفاً عبر الحزام على الفرشة التي ستمثّل الضحيّة
and then loop it around the railing, from the top.
ثمّ مرره حول السور من الأعلى
Then place that loop around the flowerpot,
وضع الحلقة حول الأصيص
pull the line to the door while keeping the flowerpot from falling,
بعدها اسحب الخيط للباب مع إمساكك الأصيص منعاً لسقوطه
and temporarily place the other loop around the intercom.
وضع الحلقة الأخرى على جهاز الاتّصال الداخلي مؤقتاً
Next, slide the victim along the line and dangle her over the edge.
تالياً، مرر الضحيّة على مسار الخيط واجعلها تتدلى من الشرفة
Naturally, he covered the victim with the mattress.
غطّى الضحية بفرشة بالطبع
It disguised the body, like camouflage.
كي يخفي الجثّة، مثل التمويه
Lastly, close the door on your way out,
بعدها أغلِق الباب عند خروجك
remove the loop around the intercom, and tie it to the nail.
انزع الحلقة حول جهاز الاتّصال الداخلي واربطها بالمسمار
Stop the nail outside the door, and it's all set.
دع المسمار عالقاً خارج الباب ويكتمل كلّ شيء
I see. Once someone opens the door,
،فهمت، عندما يفتح أحدهم الباب هكذا
one end comes undone and the victim falls by herself.
سينفكّ طرف، وتسقط الضحية تلقائياً
The door opener was Hanaoka-san's courier, of course.
من فتح الباب كان عامل التوصيل الذي طلبه هاناوكا-سان بالطبع
He would open the door at whatever time he was asked to.
سيفتح الباب في أيّ وقت حدّده له
Interesting theory, but I don't see any fishing line at all--
نظرية مثيرة للاهتمام، لكن يُفترض أن يوجد !خيط صيد إن أصاب كلامك، أين هو؟
It's simple.
الأمر بسيط
What?!
!ماذا؟
With extra line and a soy sauce bottle, it disappears like magic.
بخيط إضافيّ وعلبة صلصة صويا، سيختفي كما لو كان سحراً
First, you tie the extra line between the victim and flowerpot,
تربط الخيط الإضافيّ بين الضحيّة والأصيص أوّلاً
pull the other end through the inner and outer drain caps,
،وتمرر الطرف الآخر عبر غطاء مدخل وغطاء التصريف
and tie it to the soy sauce bottle.
وتربطه بعلبة صلصة الصويا
Then you simply place the bottle and the caps into the drain.
تُنزل بعدها صلصة الصويا في قناة التصريف فحسب
The bottle is just a weight; anything will do.
العلبة مجرد ثقل، سيفي أيّ شيء بالغرض
The saline solution missing from the refrigerator, for example.
المحلول الملحيّ الخاص بالعدسات اللاصقة المفقود من الثلاجة مثلاً
Seeing is believing... Let us open the door...
...التجربة تقطع الشكّ، فلنفتح الباب
...the door of fate that will solve this mystery!
!باب القدر الذي سيحلّ لغز هذه القضيّة
It went in!
!د-دخل
Check the drain at once!
!تفقّدوا قناة التصريف فوراً
Inspector! We already found fishing line and the saline solution!
حضرة المفتّش! وجدنا خيط الصيد !ومحلول العدسات الملحيّ سلفاً
Ridiculous! I was on the phone with her just before she fell!
!حماقة! كنتُ على الهاتف معها قبل أن تسقط
She's the one who called me!
!هي من اتّصل بي
Try redialing the office with the phone on the veranda!
فلتجربوا إعادة طلب رقم المكتب من الهاتف !الخلويّ الذي كان على الشرفة
It probably would connect.
سيتّصل به غالباً
Because you used it to call the office after preparing the previous trick.
لأنّك استعملت ذاك الهاتف للاتّصال بالمكتب بعد تنفيذ حيلتك الآنفة
And the voice that Tanaka-san heard was probably
والصوت الذي سمعه تاناكا-سان
part of the message on the answering machine in your studio.
كان جزءاً من رسالة لها على آلة الردّ الآلي في الاستوديو خاصتك على الأرجح
On your way from here to the office, you stopped by your studio,
مررت بالاستوديو في طريقك للمكتب من هنا
and took the tape with her voice on it.
وأخذت التسجيل الذي حوى صوتها
At the office, you went straight to the restroom
في المكتب، دخلت الحمّام مباشرةً
and called the office from your own cell phone.
واتّصلت بالمكتب من هاتفك الخلويّ
Hello, this is Chono.
مرحباً، أنا تشونو
After taking the call from Tanaka-san,
،بعد أخذ السمّاعة من تاناكا-سان
you diverted everyone's attention to the opposite veranda
حوّلت انتباه الجميع للشرفة المقابلة
to make it appear that the dead woman committed suicide.
لجعل سقوط مرأة ميتة سلفاً يبدو انتحاراً
The murder weapon was most likely the ashtray beneath the desk.
سلاح الجريمة الذي قتلته بها كان منفضة السجائر تحت المكتب غالباً
If you test it, it should produce a luminol reaction.
لا بدّ أن اللومينول سيعطي تفاعلاً إذا فحصتموها
Still, do you have any proof that I killed her here?
مع كلّ تحليلك، أتملك دليلاً أنّي قتلتها هنا؟
I certainly doubt it. After all, today is my first time here.
أشكّ في ذلك، فاليوم أوّل مرة آتي فيها إلى هنا
Detective Mori. Here's the hot coffee.
متحرّي موري، القهوة جاهزة
Well, Detective?
إذاً أيّها المتحرّي؟
I'll take it to him!
سأعطيها إيّاه
At any rate, I'm innocent!
!بأيّ حال، أنا بريء
Oh? What's that?
ماذا؟ ما هذا؟
What the...
...إ-إنّها
Isn't that Chono-san's signature?!
!أليس توقيع تشونو-سان؟
That's right. She drew it with nail polish while he was asleep.
صحيح، رسمته بطلاء أظافر عبثاً بينما كان هو نائماً
But how did you know about that?
لـ-لكن كيف عرفت ذلك؟
There was nail polish on the bed, yet she had none on
،كان يوجد طلاء أظافر على السرير لكن لم يكن أيّ منه على أظافرها
while Hanaoka-san had some on his finger.
بينما كان على أظافر يد هاناوكا-سان
And that nail polish went on sale today.
كما أنّ بيع طلاء الأظافر ذاك بدأ اليوم
If you're innocent, then answer this.
إذا كنت تدّعي البراءة فأجبني
When and where did you get that mark, and from whom?
متى وأين وصلتك تلك العلامة، ومن رسمها؟
It isn't true, is it, Hanaoka-san?
هـ-هذا ليس صحيحاً، أليس كذلك يا هاناوكا-سان؟
I can't believe you would kill Chono-kun...
...لا أصدّق أنك قد تقتل تشونو-كن
His motive for murder was probably his paintings.
دافع الجريمة كان رسماته غالباً
Chono-san's signature appeared many times
فتوقيع تشونو-سان ظهر مرات عديدة
beneath his own in his art album.
أسفل توقيعه الخاص في ألبوم رسماته
Those were probably works that she made using his style.
كانت رسوماً لها نفذتها متّبعةً أسلوبه غالباً
That became a point of contention...
...تحوّل ذلك لصراع
Yes! It's exactly as you say!
!أجل، كما قلت
I snapped, and when I came to, I had killed her!
فقدتُ أعصابي، وبعدما رجع عقلي !وجدت أنّي قتلتها
But that might not have been the only reason.
لكن... قد لا يكون ذاك الدافع الوحيد
I was scared. Scared of her young talent!
كنتُ خائفاً، خائفاً من موهبتها الشابة
She was a kind and beautiful girl...
كانت فتاة لطيفة وظريفة بدايةً
Almost like the butterfly that flutters around flowers!
كالفراشة التي ترفرف حول الأزهار
But she soon dominated those flowers
لكن سرعان ما هيمنتْ على تلك الأزهار
and started killing them by sucking away too much nectar!
وبدأت بقتلها بامتصاص معظم رحيقها
So I plucked her wings so she could no longer fly!
لذا نزعتُ أجنحتها... كيلا تطير مُجدداً
Eh? You want to use Dad in a commercial?!
ماذا؟ تريدون استعمال أبي في إعلان؟
I'll put him on right now!
!سأعطيه السمّاعة الآن
This is the great detective Kogoro Mori!
!أجل، معك المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
Dad's really popular! An art album and then a commercial!
!شعبية أبي عالية حقّاً! ألبوم صور والآن إعلان تلفازي
Darn it! He always gets the glory!
تبّاً، يحظى بكلِّ المجد
Hell, no! I'd never be in such a commercial!
!مستحيل! لن أظهر في إعلان كهذا أبداً
What kind of commercial was it?
أيّ إعلان كان؟
One for sleeping pills!
عن حبوب منوّمة
Said all I had to do was sleep! What nerve!
!قالوا أنّ كل ما عليّ فعله هو النوم، يا للجرأة
What do you mean? That's perfect for you!
!هذا إذاً؟ يلائمك تماماً
Is that gasoline I smell?!
!رائحة... بنزين
Why the old man? Does it have to do with the ghost ship?
لمَ العمّ؟ ألهذا علاقة بسفينة الشبح؟
No self-respecting detective would ever flee from danger!
لا مُتحرٍّ مرموق ذي احترام !قد يهرب بعد سماع كلام كهذا
Why me?!
!لـ-لمَ أنا؟
The Ghost Ship Murder Case (Part 1)
(جريمة قتل سفينة الأشباح (الجزء الأوّل
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Telescope.
منظار
Next episode is our first original multi-episode case.
!الحلقة القادمة أوّل قضيّة أصليّة من جزئين
Can you see the stars?
أيمكنك رؤية النجوم أيضاً؟